



Key Expertise

- Forensic Animation
- 3D Modeling
- Photogrammetry
- Drone Mapping
- Video Analysis
- Accident Reconstruction
- Character Animation
- 3D Scene Reconstruction
- Digital Illustration

Education

BA, Visual Effects & Motion Graphics, The Art Institute of Colorado, 2012

Level I: Forensic Video Analysis & the Law, LEVA International, 2021

Project Geographical Experience

U.S., Italy

Languages

English, Spanish

Summary of Experience

Eric King has ongoing research in the areas of camera-matching photogrammetry, videogrammetry, video analysis, photo scanning, and reality capture. He has worked in forensic animation and accident reconstruction which he performs using his vast knowledge in 3D modeling, 3D scene reconstruction and character animation. Eric regularly performs site inspections utilizing the latest in LiDAR and photogrammetric technologies. His casework is varied, providing extensive experience in many areas including vehicle accident reconstruction, railway incidents, premise liability, use of force, shooting incidents, fire cause and investigation, police misconduct and sports related injuries.

Expert/Testifying Experience

The visualization work produced for Mr. King's cases utilizing his skillsets in 3D modeling, 3D scene reconstruction, and character animation has been created specifically for mediation and trial in both state and federal cases.

Professional Affiliations/Memberships/Licenses/Training

- Certified Remote Pilot for Small Unmanned Aerial Systems (sUAS)
- SAE Member and Presenter
- LEVA level I, Kansas City Regional Police Academy, May 2019

Role at J.S. Held

Mr. King is a Video Analyst and Animator.

Contact

6070 Greenwood Plaza Blvd., Suite 200, Greenwood Village, CO 80111 | +1 303-733-1888 (O) | eking@jsheld.com



Work Experience

J.S. Held, LLC Forensic Animator 2021 – Present

Kineticorp, LLC Forensic Animator 2017 – 2021

Dish Network Producer III 2017 – 2017

Chipotle Mexican Grill Multimedia Developer 2013 – 2014

Select Project Experience

- Production of 3D animations, graphics and interactive media for depositions, mediation, and courtroom exhibits.
- 3D trajectory analysis for projectiles in shooting and use of force cases.
- Character creation, animation and tracking. Accurate creation of surrogate model including facial reconstruction and clothing. Rigging, animating and video tracking of pedestrians.
- Analysis of hundreds of cases in vehicle accident reconstruction, railway incidents, premise liability, use of force, shooting incidents, fire cause and investigation, tree fall analysis, police misconduct and sports related injuries including ski accidents.
- Site inspections utilizing the latest in LiDAR, drone mapping and photogrammetric technologies to locate and document physical evidence and scene features for further analysis.
- Experience with cases involving complex industrial equipment and as well as large industrial facilities.
- Video Synchronization of surveillance, dash-cam, body warn-cam videos. Utilizes audio and visual cues as well as timecode and metadata to synch large sets of provided video in a lossless manner for 3d analysis.
- Video tracking for speed analysis and visualization
- Extensive experience in creating 3d models using photogrammetry in Reality Capture. On large as well as a small scale.

Selected Publications

- Terpstra, T., Mckelvey, N., King, E., Hashemian, A., King, C., "Aerial Photoscanning with Ground Control Points from USGS LiDAR." SAE, Paper 2022-01-0833. Detroit, MI. (2022). Recognized as one of the best publications from SAE World Congress 2022 and published in the SAE International Journal of Advances and Current Practices in Mobility.
- 2. Terpstra, T., Neale, W.T.C., Owens, T., **King, E.**, Bier S., Voitel, T., "An Analysis of Body-Worn Camera Photogrammetry Using Depth Mapping." *Proceedings of the American Academy of Forensic Sciences*, 73rd Annual Scientific Meeting, Held Virtually. 2021. C21.
- 3. Terpstra, T., Neale, W.T.C., **King, E.**, Hashemian, A., Hessel, D., "Determining Range of Certainty in Photogrammetry and Videogrammetry." Proceedings of the American Academy of Forensic Sciences, 73rd Annual Scientific Meeting, Held Virtually. 2021. C21.
- 4. Terpstra, T., Hashemian, A., Gillihan, R., King, E. Miller, S., Neale W.T.C., "Accuracies in Single Image Camera Matching Photogrammetry." SAE, Paper 2021-01-0888. Detroit, MI. (2021).

Awards

Eric King, BA

Visual Analyst I, Forensics



Student of the quarter for Visual Effects & Motion Graphics, Summer & Fall 2011

AIC Award of Excellence for Demo Reel 2012

AIC Reel Thing: Student Animation and Video Festival Summer 2012 Entries: Gundam, Bridge Removal, Transit